让我们看看实现一个非常
Let's take a look at what it will
基本的SyncAdapter需要做些什么。我们会
take to implement a very basic SyncAdapter. We're going
写两个服务。每一个服务的主要
to write two services. Each service serves the primary
目的是送一个表示Android Binder接口的对象
purpose of delivering an object that represents an Android
给一个系统框架
Binder interface to one of the system frameworks.
Binder实际上是低层次胶水 帮助在
A Binder is actually the low-level glue that implements
在Android系统里实现线程间的交流。每一次你使用
cross process communication in Android. You've been using Binders
Android系统服务时都有用到Binder
every time you talk to an Android system service.
Intent和ContentProvider是基于Binder接口
Intents and content providers are just high-level abstractions on
之上的高层次抽象。有一个叫AIDL的语言
top of the Binder interface. There's a whole language known
被用来帮助定义这些接口。我们不会
as AIDL to help define these interfaces. We're not
在这里讲到所有的，但是利用服务和Binder
going to cover all this here, but there's a lot
你已经可以做很多东西了。
more you can do with services and Binders. One
在我们开始前最后一件事，我们会定义一下
more thing before we start, we're going to define an
一个认证器服务和一个认证器。但是它只会
Authenticator Service and an Authenticator. But it will only
被Android的账户框架用以允许我们
be used by the Android accounts framework to allow us
创建新的账户。SyncAdapter需要一个账户
to create an account. SyncAdaptor's need an account.
并且账户框架要求
And the account framework requires that there be
认证服务提供一个认证器
an authenticator delivered by an authenticator Service. You'll
你会看到我们的认证器只是一系列
see that our authenticator is just a series
的Stub。它们会在每次被调用时丢出
of stubs, with exceptions that get thrown for
异常。这样没有异常的话就能证明
each call just to prove that it isn't
它没有被用到。最后一点，这一个章节几乎
really used. One final note. This section approximately
是照着developer.android.com上的线上教程来讲SyncAdapter的
follows the online training at developer.android.com around sync adapters.
所以如果有什么问题的话
Feel free to look there if you have
可以去那里看看。我们将创建一个新的
any more questions. We're going to create a new
包：sync，它将包括所有这些东西
package, sync, to house all of this goodness.
然后为我们的认证器创建一个新的类
And a new class file for our authenticator. This
我们要粘贴进来的这段代码
code that we're about to paste in really
完全从developer.android.com website拷贝的
just comes from the developer.android.com website, and as I
像我刚才说的 它只是一个stub。
mentioned earlier it's just a stub. You can tell
因为调用任何这些函数都会丢出一个异常
because we throw exceptions for calling any of the
除了构造函数
functions except for the constructor. And one
然后另一个文件：SunshineAuthenticatorService 这个会有多一些
more file. Create SunshineAuthenticatorService. This is more code
代码是专门写来我们用的。它允许
that is written for us. It allows
账户经理访问这个空的认证器
the account manager to access the empty authenticator
我们刚刚粘贴进来的那个。现在我们在strings.xml里添加账户类型
that we just pasted in. Now we add the account type in our strings.xml. The
这个账户类型字符串建议它是专门供
account type string suggests that it is specific
我们的APP使用的。如果我们有很多程序
to our app. If we had many applications
用同一个账户，我们会想
using the same account, we might want
创建一个example.com账户。我们会
to create just an example.com account. We'll also
清理不需要的东西然后添加
begin to clean things up and add
一个content_authority字符串。注意，这个和
a content authority string. Note that this matches
我们的内容提供商字符串保持一致。我们一会会修整这个XML文件 让它们都用
our content provider string. We'll fix the XML file later so they both use
这同一个字符串。创建一个新的XML素材文件，文件名是
this same string. We create a new XML resource file, filename
authenticator.xml，Root Element：account-authenticator
authenticator.xml, with root element account-authenticator.
你可能注意到了，SunshineAuthenticatorService
And you probably noticed that SunshineAuthenticatorService is
实际上需要在AndroidManifest.xml里
actually a service that needs to be registered
跟包经理注册。
with a package manager in AndroidManifest.xml. Here's
这里这些就是做这个事儿的
some more pasty goodness that does just that.
现在要非常非常小心。这些字符串
Now be very, very careful. These strings
必须要精确地保持一致。系统为
all have to match precisely. The error messages
这种不正确的账户而报出的错误信息
that the system gives for having incorrect accounts
是很不直观的。有了这些，
are not necessarily intuitive. And with that you
你应该能创建出有效账户。重申一下，
should be able to create valid accounts. Once again,
这些只是把SyncAdapter和
this is all just so that the SyncAdapter can be
账户连接起来。你实际上并不会真正用到
tied to an account. You don't actually use this
好了，我们来调整一下manifest里的provider标签
at all. All right, let's tweak our provider tag in
我们要加上syncable属性
the manifest. We're going to add the syncable attribute.
这让Android知道我们打算让
This just lets Android know that we're planning to synchronize
这个内容提供商和服务器同步。然后我们设置
the content provider with the server. Also, we'll set
android:exported=false。 我们在默认设置里设置了
android:exported equals false. We had it at the default setting.
这意味着其他APP也能读取到我们的内容。最后，
Which means that other apps could see our content. Finally,
我们把authorities改成我们新的字符串。
let's change the authority to use our new string. Now
现在来做一些特殊的许可权。我们需要能
for some additional permissions. We need to be able to
读取和写入同步配置。这是能理解的。我们也
read and write sync settings. That makes sense. We also
必须验证用户， 尽管我们不会真正用到
have to authenticate accounts, even though we're not really using
这些在任何情况下。这些许可权都不是它的用户
them for anything. None of these permissions are one's users
应该关心的。但是作为开发者，我们总是想要
should be concerned about. But as developers, we always want
非常小心 当我们添加新的许可的时候
to be careful when we have to add new permissions.
接下来在sync文件夹里创建SunshineSyncAdapter文件
Let's create the SunshineSyncAdapter file itself inside
它是从AbstractThreadedSyncAdapter继承来的
of sync, which extends the abstract threaded sync
按Ctrl+I 然后按Ctrl+O
adapter class. Hit Ctrl+I and then Ctrl+O
这帮助我们在构建函数里创建所有需要的抽象函数
to implement the necessary abstract methods in constructor.
我们会使用这第一个构建函数。我们会
We'll use the first constructor. We'll fill
晚一些来完成这个。你可能能回想起
this out later. As you may recall, the
这个SyncAdapter模式还需要另一个服务。
sync adaptor pattern requires yet another service. So
我们创建另一个类 叫做SunshineSyncService
we're going to create another Java class called SunshineSyncService.
这个类是用来传递SyncAdapterBinder给SyncManager的
This class is used to deliver the sync adapter Binder to the sync manager.
这个Binder是被
The Binder is implemented for us by
AbstractThreadedSyncAdapter创建的 然后
the abstract threaded sync adapter class. And returned
通过getSyncAdapterBinder返回。现在我们
in the getSyncAdapterBinder method. And now, we
需要多一个XML文件。创建syncadapter.xml
need one more XML file. Create syncadapter.xml with
Root element：sync-adapter。重申一次，这个XML
root element sync-adapter. Once again, this XML
定义和sync-adapter相关的配置
file defines the settings associated with our sync-adapter.
包括它的内容方，以及同步的账户类型
Including its content authority. The account type that it
对用户是否可见、
syncs. Whether or not it's user visible. Whether it
是否支持上传。这会改变内容提供商
supports uploading, which changes the way the content provider
和SyncAdapter的交互方式。是否允许多线程同步，以及
interacts with the sync adapter. Allowing parallel syncs and is
是否总是可同步的。这些配置对于这一个APP都是有意义的
always syncable. These settings make sense for this particular
我打赌你知道接下来是什么
application, and I bet you know what comes next. You're
是的，你必须向包经理注册
right. You have to register the sync adapter service
这个SyncAdapter服务。因此我们不得不创建
with the package manager. And therefore we have to create
更多的manifest项目，包括一些重要的元数据
more manifest entries, containing some important metadata. Most
最重要的是要和我们刚刚创建的文件连接起来
importantly, links to the file we just created. All
好了，我们就快完成了。让我们开始直接在
right, now we're getting close. Let's start working
SyncAdapter上工作吧。我们首先
on the sync adapter, itself. We'll start with a
用这个辅助函数来获取一个假的同步账户
helper function to get the dummy sync account
并且确保它已经被创建好了。然后，
and make sure that it has been created. Then,
给我们的SyncAdapter添加另外一个辅助函数
we'll add another helper function to our sync adaptor,
以便能更容易测试我们的SyncAdapter
to make it easier to test our sync adaptor.